James RT Bossert

linkedin.com/in/jrtb jrbosser@gmail.com

(919) 360-9296

I'm a passionate and empathetic leader who thrives in collaborative environments where diversity, creativity, and curiosity are valued most. My 25+ year career in software engineering includes directing teams at a fast-paced consulting agency, accelerating software delivery for Fortune 50 clients, co-founding a successful mobile gaming business, and managing an enterprise instructional technology department. I embrace a growth mindset in everything I do, and I'm ready for my next big challenge!

EXPERIENCE

WillowTree, Durham, NC — *Group VP and Managing Director*

JUNE 2023 - FEBRUARY 2024

- Responsible for 20+ client accounts and teams with a combined \$75M+ in yearly revenue.
- Evolved and built a highly performing engineering discipline across 4 client portfolios, 4 US offices, and 2 offices in Brazil.
- Effectively communicated and built relationships with C-level stakeholders at Fortune 500 clients.
- Oversaw performance and resource management for a distributed team of 50+ engineering directors and 400+ engineers.
- As managing director for the Durham, NC office, I led a team that created a vibrant, welcoming, and unique hybrid office culture for 150+ employees. I proactively led and supported employee engagement initiatives to enhance retention.

WillowTree, Durham, NC — Partner and VP, Engineering

JULY 2022 - JUNE 2023

- Managed a portfolio of 5-6 client accounts and teams with a combined \$20M+ in yearly revenue.
- Coached leaders and teams through difficult client and employee conversations. Negotiated scope and timelines during delivery.
 Deepened the team's understanding of client business drivers, KPIs, user needs, and budget to align our solutions effectively.
- Managed engineering initiatives, including establishing and maintaining job descriptions/rubrics/career ladders, engineering newsletter+blog, interviewing/hiring, bi-annual performance evaluations, practice advisors, innovation hour, and our engineering internship program.

WillowTree, Durham, NC — Principal Software Engineer / Associate Engineering Director / Engineering Director

JANUARY 2020 - JULY 2022

 Established a proven track record of leading successful projects and larger teams working across a wide variety of platforms.

SKILLS

Empowering high-performing teams

Mentoring engineering leaders

Setting high expectations

Leading with energy and enthusiasm

Creating an inclusive work environment

Fostering a culture of accountability

Hiring, interviewing, recruiting, retention

Resource management

CI/CD, TDD, Agile, Scrum

Simplifying complex problems

Technology thought leadership

Stakeholder relationship management

User-centered product design

Optimizing for performance and scalability

Change management

Innovation and creativity

Regulatory compliance and security

Conflict resolution

- Led high-profile projects, including building the Vitality One fitness rewards app and growing to \$7M in yearly revenue working with Anheuser-Busch to digitally transform their suite of CRM apps.
- Led the team that built Vocable, a free award-winning app that allows those with conditions such as MS, stroke, ALS, or spinal cord injuries to communicate by tracking head movements.

WillowTree, Durham, NC — iOS Software Engineer / iOS Platform Software Engineer / iOS Senior Software Engineer

AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2020

- Directed and delegated efforts to team members, multiplying their effectiveness. Provided positive and constructive feedback, and mentored others in growth areas. Led client communications and owned complex technical discussions. Owned contributions to the mobile iOS platform and worked closely with other platforms on multiple projects to maximize team effectiveness.
- Lead iOS contributor in launching National Geographic's streaming and magazine app in the US.
- Contributed to the online check-in feature for the Wyndham Hotels iOS app.

Fairlady Media — Co-Founder and Lead Developer

2008 - PRESENT

- Co-created the hugely popular Grandma and Grandpa kid's brand on the App Store. Currently 13 apps in the series with 7 figures in sales, 4M+ downloads, strong support from Apple including multiple App Store front-page features, and numerous design accolades including 12 Editor's Choice awards from Children's Technology Review.
- Consulted and developed apps for clients including Sesame Street (Monster at the End of This Book), Houghton Mifflin Harcourt (Curious George), Hearst, Callaway Digital, Mobiquity, Sanrio (Hello Kitty), and American Greetings (Strawberry Shortcake, Care Bears).
- As lead developer, I focused on Apple native development tools including Xcode, Objective-C, Swift, Cocos2d, and SpriteKit.

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC — *Technical Manager / Senior Instructional Technologist*

1994 - 2015

- Developer and systems administrator for NC State's academic and extension CMS. Led the pilot, implementation, and production teams for NC State's Enterprise Learning Management System, Moodle (Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP, Red Hat Enterprise Linux).
- Developed key enterprise performance analytics and reporting for university and college-level academic programs.
- Technical PM with oversight and management of mission-critical enterprise IT systems and development projects for NC State.
 Supervised a team of seven full-time staff and mentored students.
- Led the pilot, implementation, and production teams for NC State's previous generation Enterprise LMS, Blackboard Vista (Java, Sun Microsystems Unix).

EDUCATION

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

INTERESTS

Traveling the US by RV

Organic chili pepper farming

All things Coffee

Astrophotography

Maker, DIY, Arduino

Reading science fiction